# **Sakib Chowdhury**

# Graduate Research Fellow & PhD Student in Robotics, Former Machine Learning Research Engineer

Experienced in the intersection of robotics and machine learning.

Experienced in multimodal computer vision and natural language models.

Currently studying robot perception for high speed decision making and controller design.

M: sakibchowdhury131@gmail.com

**T:** +12014486568

**A:** 282 3rd St, Jersey City, New Jersey

07302

W: https://sakibchowdhuryl31.github.io

#### Education

#### Stevens Institute of Technology

PhD Student (Studying Robotics)

Bangladesh University of Engineering and Technology

Bachelors, Department of EEE

New Jersey, USA

07/2023 - Present

New Jersey, USA

03/2017 - 03/2022

#### **Publications**

Google Scholar

- <u>SpectroCardioNet: An Attention Based Deep Learning Network Using Triple-Spectrograms of PCG Signal for Cardiac Disease Detection</u>
- A Simulated Intelligent Pixelated Electrode Array for Surface Electromyography Sensors
- <u>CovTANet</u>: a hybrid tri-level attention based network for lesion segmentation, diagnosis, and severity prediction of COVID-19 chest CT scans
- SynthNID: Synthetic Data to Improve End-to-end Bangla Document Key Information Extraction
- SHONGLAP: A Large Bengali Open-Domain Dialogue Corpus

#### **WORK HISTORY**

#### **Graduate Research Fellow**

Stevens Institute of Technology

New Jersey, USA

07/2023 - Present

- Studying robot motion control in complex dynamic scenarios
- Studying policy design for learning table tennis with robotic arm

## Research Engineer (Machine Learning)

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Celloscope

11/2021 - 07/2023

- Designed vision transformer based text extraction systems from Bangla document images
- Designed Bangla speech-to-speech chatbot for banking application, e.g., fund transfer, balance inquiry, FAQ etc.
- Designed voice signature based speaker verification system

#### **Assistant Researcher**

Dhaka, Bangladesh

#### Bangladesh University of Engineering and Technology

11-2020 - 03-2021

• Developed a system that detects derailment from upto 1200 meters distance by sensing the vibrations generated from the movement of train.

## Intern Engineer (Hardware Design)

Adorsho Praisheba Ltd.

Dhaka, Bangladesh

07-2017 - 11-2020

• Contributed to the development of BOLUS, an AI powered IoT hardware that is swallowed by the cattle in cowsheds. It monitors the health condition of the cow and a farmer can track the health report with a smartphone.